{
  "reference_number": "12152",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a goal to reach net zero emissions by the second half of the century and the Climate Change Commission advises on the specific target for the Government to set later",
      "answer_index": 11,
      "notes": "The goal must be that of a balanced outcome. A goal of Zero maybe good for the environmental side, however devastating from an\n\n economical side. There must be some common ground where a realistic and achievable target/goal can be met. Any advise given\n must be done so from a group with full representation. Meaning all affected parties/sectors have a voice/say. An intention/movement\n towards continual reduction YOY aposed to set time frames is more achivable."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Long-Lived Gases and Stabilised Short-Lived Gases - Long-lived gases to net zero by 2050 while also stabilising short-lived gases",
      "answer_index": 12,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Everything need to reviewable, particularly with some many contributors outside of our control. In addition to continual advances in\n technology and methods of operation."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Continued reductions YOY would provide a better outcome hence only requiring a line drawn in the sand as to ones current level of\n\n emission. This level being there max with the goal/requirement of continual reductions YOY."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Similar to above, best outcome is for continual reductions."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Similar to above, best outcome is for continual reductions."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "No weighting must be given to those processes of which produce emissions to create a renewable product vs those producing none\n\nrenewable products."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The law of diminishing returns will apply in an attempt to reduce emissions, if a balanced outcome as stated in question one is to be\n\nachieved."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The generation most affected by these changes need to have a voice. So called farming/rural representatives having take part in\ndiscussions thus far are in my opinion not true/ fair representation of the generation o be most significantly impacted. These are\n\nolder farmers who have made their fortunes and have acquired large land holdings. They have capacity/ ability to absorb additional\ncost/restriction which affect profitability where as the younger/next generation of farmers doesn't. This may also apply in none rural\nbased industries."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "But only is the each sector has fair and suitable representation and voting rights."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Who is the most negatively impacted should have equal representation."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    }
  ]
}
